<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: geek | WATCH AND LEARN]]></title>
  <link href="http://raejin.com/blog/categories/geek/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://raejin.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-19T15:26:02-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://raejin.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rae Liu]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Readings for the summer]]></title>
    <link href="http://raejin.com/blog/2013/05/19/readings-for-the-summer/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-19T14:32:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://raejin.com/blog/2013/05/19/readings-for-the-summer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello! Summer 2013 officially started :-)</p>

<p>Today is the second day of the summer, and I feel pretty good about having a fresh start despite the fact that I did waste yesterday just to have beers with my friends. All in all, life's good after the final exams, YAY!</p>

<p>This summer I will be working on Ruby on Sinatra, along with some light-weight front-end framework. Therefore, in order to get ready for my internship, I am setting up a reading list so that I don't just blindly work on something without understanding the fundamentals.</p>

<p>Although I don't think the project I will be working on requires any kind of sophisticated front-end work, I still want to learn the trendy hipster-ish front-end JavaScript frameworks like <a href="http://angularjs.org">AngularJS</a>, <a href="http://knockoutjs.com">KnockoutJS</a>, or <a href="http://emberjs.com">EmberJS</a>.</p>

<p>Here is the reading list of the books and the useful tutorials:</p>

<h3>Online resources</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLP6DbQBkn9ymGQh2qpk9ImLHdSH5T7yw7">AngularJS video tutorial on Egghead.io</a></li>
<li><a href="http://contribute.jquery.org/style-guide/js/">JavaScript Style Guide by jQuery</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/airbnb/javascript">Airbnb JavaScript Style Guide (Re-read again)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://rubysource.com/rails-development-101-rvm/">Rails Intro, Deep Dive: RVM</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.sinatrarb.com/intro.html">Sinatra Intro</a></li>
<li><a href="http://sass-lang.com/">Sass</a></li>
<li><a href="http://haml.info/">Haml</a></li>
<li><a href="http://coffeescript.org/">CoffeeScript</a></li>
</ul>


<h3>Books reference</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920019664.do">Sinatra: Up and Running</a></li>
<li><a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/9780596517748.do">JavaScript The Good Parts</a></li>
<li><a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/9780596529307.do">High Performance Web Sites - Essential Knowledge for Front-End Engineers</a></li>
<li><a href="http://ruby.railstutorial.org/">Ruby on Rails Tutorial, Second Edition</a></li>
<li><a href="http://pragprog.com/book/ruby3/programming-ruby-1-9">Programming Ruby: The Pragmatic Programmers' Guide</a></li>
</ul>


<p>So far I found Ruby very magical and pseudo-intuitive to learn, but as coming from a less-dynamic programming language, I sometimes found I am doing too much work for what should've been done in two lines of code. I need to practice write less code in Ruby to achieve maximum efficiency. I will continue to update this list as I found useful resources.</p>

<p>It's already a great start, cheers Rae!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SelfControl saves my final grades]]></title>
    <link href="http://raejin.com/blog/2013/05/15/selfcontrol-saves-my-final-grades/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-15T07:54:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://raejin.com/blog/2013/05/15/selfcontrol-saves-my-final-grades</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Alright, I know the title is a bit off. I could've still suffered if I don't study well enough to handle the finals. I've discovered a OSX application called SelfControl to prevent me from wondering on social websites occasionally for a period of time.</p>

<p><a href="http://selfcontrolapp.com/">This app</a> is really awesome if you are the kind of person like me who lacks self-discipline whenever there is a need to focus. Well, mainly the reason is I don't really like the material and it is hard in general, so that pushed me off from being proactive about the finals.</p>

<p>Fortunately, this app is powerful enough to keep me from cracking the rules. It claims that after the rules are set, there is no way to break the rules even uninstalling the app. So there you have it! In case someone is looking for some help to get focused studying for exams.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How long does it take a noob to master UNIX commands?]]></title>
    <link href="http://raejin.com/blog/2013/04/25/unixnoob/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-25T19:52:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://raejin.com/blog/2013/04/25/unixnoob</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This semester I am taking a self-paced UNIX class, which is a lot more fun compared to the other theoretical-ish computer courses. Sometimes I really lack motivation to learn effective UNIX commands to make my life easier. And I don't think I'm alone, but in order to be a legit software enginner I must at least not suck at the basics.</p>

<p>Last week I ran to an UNIX tutor asking some dumb questions from the text, and I finally realized that piping is not restricted to a single input command! I wonder why it took me so long to notice this trivial fact, why!!!!????</p>

<p>Here it goes, I need to remind myself how dumb I was/am and hopefully I stay motivated to be an effective engineer.</p>

<p><code>
$ cat someFile | comm -12 - anotherFile
</code></p>

<p>It's the hyphen that makes this works beautifully! Who would have thought of using hyphen? Who?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hex color picker for Mac]]></title>
    <link href="http://raejin.com/blog/2013/04/06/hex-color-picker-for-mac/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-06T00:05:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://raejin.com/blog/2013/04/06/hex-color-picker-for-mac</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Whenever I need to decide a specific color to use, I always consult my sweet Photoshop CS6 since it runs pretty smooth on my laptop. But this is an overkill, opening up Photoshop simply for picking a color sounds so stupid and I've been doing this for years.</p>

<p>Luckily, I stumble upon <a href="http://yuji.wordpress.com/2010/08/01/mac-adding-hex-color-picker-to-color-picker/">this article</a> about how to configure a light-weight hex color picker app on a Mac. Although the article clearly maps out all the steps, I am still presenting it here:</p>

<ol>
<li>Download <a href="http://wafflesoftware.net/hexpicker/">Hex Color Picker</a></li>
<li>Open AppleScript Editor</li>
<li>Write the desired app name i.e. <code>ColorPicker</code></li>
<li>Save as a file with <code>.app</code> as file extension</li>
<li>Move the file <code>HexColorPicker.colorPicker</code> to <code>~/Library/ColorPickers</code></li>
</ol>


<p>Simple, elegant, no more Photoshop :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
